Yingxue Zhang

Binghamton University Address: 129 Passaic Ave, APT 301, Kearny, NJ 07032

Computer Science Department Email: yzhang42@binghamton.edu
Engineering Building, N04 Homepage: https://yingxuezhang.com
4400 Vestal Pkwy E Github: https://github.com/yingxue-zhang

Binghamton, NY 13902 Phone: +1 (551) 263-9462

Research Summary

Broad research interests include: (1) designing novel data mining, machine learning and AI techniques to solve spatial-temporal big data analytics problems related to smart cities, public safety, sustainability and business, and (2) human behavior analysis and decision making with meta-learning, reinforcement learning and imitation learning.

Work Experience

Binghamton University, Binghamton, NY

Assistant Professor Aug 2022-Present

Nuro, Mountain View, CA

Research Intern May 2021-Aug 2021

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA

Teaching Assistant Jan 2020-May 2022

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA

Research Assistant Aug 2018-Jan 2020

Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI), Worcester, MA Aug 2018-May 2022

Ph.D., Data Science, Data Science Department

Thesis: Spatial-Temporal Generative Adversarial Learning.

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ Aug 2016-May 2018

M.S., Financial Engineering (Data Science Track), School of Business

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China Sep 2012-July 2016

B.E., Computer Science, School of Electronic, Information and Electrical Engineering

Teaching Experience Computer Science Department, Binghamton University

Instructor Aug 2022-Present

 ${\it Courses}\hbox{: Python and Data Mining (INFO 501), Applied Data Mining (INFO 535),}$

Applied Machine Learning (INFO 536)

Data Science Department, Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Teaching Assistant Jan 2020-May 2022 Courses: Database Management Systems (CS 542), Reinforcement Learning (DS 595)

Foisie Business School, Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Guest Lecturer May 2021

Course: Introduction to Data Science (DS1010)

Conference Publications

- [C1] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. STrans-GAN: Spatially-Transferable Generative Adversarial Networks for Urban Traffic Estimation. 2022 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [C2] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou and Jun Luo. Mest-GAN: Cross-City Urban Traffic Estimation with Meta Spatial-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks. 2022 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [C3] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Zhenming Liu and Jun Luo. C^3 -GAN: Complex-Condition-Controlled Urban Traffic Estimation through Generative Adversarial Networks. 2021 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [C4] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Curb-GAN: Conditional Urban Traffic Estimation through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD' 20).
- [C5] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou and Jun Luo. cST-ML: Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning for Traffic Dynamics Prediction. 2020 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [C6] Han Bao, Xun Zhou, Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Yiqun Xie. COVID-GAN: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 Pandemic through Spatio-Temporal Conditional Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGSPATIAL International Conference on Advances in Geographic Information Systems.
- [C7] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Traffic-GAN: Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation with Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks. 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).

Journal Publications

- [J1] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Jun Luo and Zhi-Li Zhang. Urban Traffic Dynamics Prediction A Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning Approach. In ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST).
- [J2] Han Bao, Xun Zhou, Yiqun Xie, Yingxue Zhang and Yanhua Li. COVID-GAN+: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks with Enhanced Features. In ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST).
- [J3] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation A Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks Approach. In IEEE Transactions on Big Data (TBD).

Conference IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Presentations Conference Presenter

Orlando, Florida, Nov 2022

Topic 1: STrans-GAN: Spatially-Transferable Generative Adversarial Networks for Urban Traffic Estimation,

Topic 2: Mest-GAN: Cross-City Urban Traffic Estimation with Meta Spatial-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks.

IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Conference Presenter

Virtual event, Nov 2021

Topic: C^3 -GAN: Complex-Condition-Controlled Urban Traffic Estimation through Generative Adversarial Networks.

IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Conference Presenter Virtual event, Nov 2020

Topic: cST-ML: Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning for Traffic Dynamics

Prediction.

ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining

Conference Presenter Virtual event, Aug 2020

Topic: Curb-GAN: Conditional Urban Traffic Estimation through Spatio-Temporal

Generative Adversarial Networks.

IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Conference Presenter Beijing, China, Nov 2019

Topic: Traffic-GAN: Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation with Traffic Generative

Adversarial Networks.

Mentoring Mentor for Yiqing Zhang, Ph.D. student in Data Science, WPI Spring 2021

Experience Project: Activity-Based Travel Demand Modelling for Urban Planning

> Mentor for Zixuan Zhang, Graduate student in Data Science, WPI Fall 2020

Project: Spatial-Temporal Data Analytics For Travel Demand Prediction

Awards ICDM 2020 Student Travel Award 2020

> ACM SIGKDD Student Registration Award 2020

> Scholarship for International Students, Stevens Institute Technology 2016-2017

Academic Reviewer for AAAI (2020, 2021), WWW (2020,2021) IJCAI (2019, 2020, 2021), Service

KDD (2019, 2020, 2021, 2022), SDM (2020, 2021), ICLR 2021, CIKM (2019, 2020,

2021), ICDM (2020,2021)

Technical Python, R, C/C++

Skills PyTorch, TensorFlow, LATEX, Matlab, SQL